Thorin: How's it going, man?
Thorin: Oh, you're muted.
Thorin: Let me turn on my light, it's here somewhere.
Grygum: Whoa, whoa?
Thorin: Hello!
Thorin: You're still muted, man.
Daz: Yeah, Zoom is being done. It won't… I found a way to unmute myself, but it wouldn't let me, it wouldn't let me bring my… like, I was trying to make sure I was on the latest version and find where settings are now, and I can't find it, but in addition to that, it was, once I brought that other window up, it, like.
Daz: yeeted this whole thing up into a little bitty window in the upper right-hand corner of my screen that I couldn't see.
Daz: Anyway.
Thorin: I don't use Zoom every day anymore, I, like, most of our company runs on Hangouts, and so, like…
Thorin: I get…
Grygum: Jeez.
Grygum: I didn't realize Hangouts was still around.
Thorin: Or Google Meet or whatever, I don't know, it's the same damn thing.
Daz: Yeah.
Thorin: Google Talk, that's what I… that's what I worked on, that's what we called it, I don't know.
Grygum: There's, there's one, one person I, I talked to over,
Grygum: Google… whatever it's called, and that's my sister in Japan.
Grygum: I… I don't know why, but it seems to be what we settled on.
Daz: I, I use it for a science… science fiction book club month thing. We all get on Google Meet for that.
Daz: And then, at work, I use WebEx.
Daz: Because I work for.
Grygum: Well…
Thorin: I'm sorry.
Grygum: Well, it.
Thorin: WebEx is, like, literally the worst.
Daz: It's gotten a lot better, but it's still not great. It's better than Teams.
Thorin: Oh, teams…
Thorin: See, I log into Teams, and I'm like, there's always something fucked up with, like, Microsoft accounts and stuff, and I can never figure it out. So I always give up, and I'm just like, just do the web thing, and don't bother logging in.
Daz: Right.
Grygum: See, I always think of this radio program committee meeting where somebody had written this paper that was all about, you know, here's this great video conferencing product we could make.
Grygum: And the person talking about the paper listed off all the lists of features that they wanted. And then somebody else in the program committee stood up and said, you know, WebEx actually has all those features, we just don't pay for them.
Grygum: And we shut down the paper like that.
Grygum: I really…
Daz: I really wish you could do it. I will say one thing about WebEx that it does bet… probably better than Zoom. It works very well if you have a very shitty internet connection.
Daz: It will just drop the frame rate to, like, 3 frames a second, and keep the audio going.
Thorin: Oh, yeah.
Daz: It won't just…
Thorin: Prioritize audio, yeah.
Daz: Yeah.
Thorin: Ow.
Thorin: Aye, aye, aye.
Thorin: How y'all doing? Anything new going on?
Daz: My, my whole company.
Grygum: Ugh.
Daz: New York, so…
Daz: I used to work… it's a… you guys… do you guys remember Tom Gillis, the GM for NSX and security?
Thorin: Yeah.
Grygum: Yeah, yeah, I, I, I do.
Daz: I… I worked for Craig Connors, who was, like, the guy that came in with BellaCloud. I worked for him under Tom, and Tom…
Daz: just got, switched out as the GM for that group, because they did a big reorg under all of the product stuff, and is going to be A'lai's new CTO.
Thorin: What… I wonder, like, what does the job of a CTO look like at a company?
Daz: So, I think for… I mean, Tom's technical in that, like, early in his career, he wrote, like, guidance software for the Patriot missiles.
Daz: But, like, hasn't really done… like, then he went into the business side of things and stayed in the business side the whole time.
Daz: So I think he's in more of the chief talking officer side, like, where he's, you know…
Thorin: to CTOs, and, like, they all pretend that they used to be engineers.
Daz: Yeah.
Daz: Yeah, so there's some of that going on, but…
Thorin: My favorite was every time that, that,
Thorin: God, I'm blanking on his name!
Thorin: like, old CEO of VMware…
Daz: Grygum?
Thorin: What's that?
Thorin: No, no, What's that? No, the one that bought our company, I'm blanking on his name.
GM: Hawk 10?
Thorin: No, the one before that. They bought our company as in Heptio.
Grygum: Gelsinger?
Thorin: Yeah, yeah. So every time Pat would talk, he would love to talk about how he's still a real engineer, and we'd all nod along, like, yeah, dude, you're still, like, you know, you're super technical still, don't worry, like… and he would start, like, he'd be talking software, he's like, yeah, I really, you know, I would talk speeds and feeds, I'm like, that's not a thing in software. We don't, we don't do speeds and feeds and software.
Grygum: You know, at my, at my startup at Nassera… Those of us who work.
GM: on speeds and feeds and software raise a hand in objection.
Grygum: We both agree.
GM: Wait, wait. Just for the record…
Thorin: CNC control software? I mean, like…
GM: But we… some of us did worry about speeds and feats, but we will… we will digress.
Daz: I wrote… I wrote the very first ever…
Daz: data plane for a network service device, basically a firewall, that was embedded in a modular switch.
Daz: And that, you very much had to worry about speeds and feeds.
Thorin: Well, what do speeds and feeds mean in that context?
Daz: Basically, I have a backplane that can throw 256 gigabits at me, and I'm trying to keep up, and all I can actually do is about a gigabit.
Thorin: No, speeds and feeds, you're talking about CNC, where you actually have things spinning, which is the speed.
Daz: Oh, right, right, right.
Thorin: Speed is, like, how fast you move.
Daz: move it across the board.
Thorin: part.
Daz: Yeah, people stole it in the network world.
Thorin: Oh, okay.
Daz: It feeds to mean, like, bandwidth and, and, like, yeah.
GM: Yeah.
Daz: So, that had moved from machine shops into networking parlance.
GM: Yes, that's literally where I stumbled across it as well, where I worked on a network packet thing that shipped, the gigabit network speeds on a Celeron.
Thorin: Okay.
Thorin: Yeah, and all the networking people got pissed off that we took over the term control plane.
GM: Well, we give them credit.
Grygum: Oh,
GM: Yes.
Grygum: GM, can you accept my friend request on Discord so I can add some DMs with.
GM: Oh, which one, who are you?
Grygum: My, Woggle Bug, that's my, my discard name.
GM: Why do I not have you?
Grygum: I don't know.
Grygum: I don't see…
Thorin: Why is 1Password not letting me log in?
Grygum: Discord basically hides the friend requests, so you have to dig a bit to even find them.
GM: That's pending.
GM: We weren't fun… we weren't friends until today. How sad.
Grygum: Well, it's almost meaningless on Discord, except for DMing people who you aren't in a common server with, something like that.
GM: Yes.
GM: It's always very fascinating.
Thorin: So my computer was off long enough that 1Password needed to be restarted twice to update multiple times.
Grygum: That would make it 2Password.
Thorin: I know, right?
Daz: Just.
GM: Just for the… just for the, the record.
GM: Just for the record, Daz, you never worked at a startup? I don't think I quite understood that.
Daz: So, I… I worked at a very small company.
Daz: So, I did a startup-y thing.
Daz: When I was at UT, and I was getting my electrical engineering degree, there was this entrepreneur guy that has, like, a serial entrepreneur, he starts a bunch of different companies. He… this is… I'm gonna try to condense this story as small as possible. He was at IBM selling them, process equipment for a company he repped.
Daz: And they had this laser that had all these… this laser chassis thing, and it had all these stickers on it saying, do not use decommissioning body. And he asked what happened. Somebody didn't follow the rules, and they overrode the thing, and it caused a safety incident, and it was, like, a nitty and gag 100-watt laser with, like, a 4-axis
Daz: robot.
Thorin: Now we're talking speeds and feeds.
Daz: Now we're talking speed to speed. And he bought it from them. He's like, well, what are you guys gonna do with it? And they're like, we're just gonna decommission to get out of here. And, like, he bought it from them for cheap. And then he paid to get it moved.
Daz: And then he had this bright idea, because he was all involved in surface mount stuff, of, like, when you build…
Grygum: 100-watt lasers are very bright.
Daz: Yes, very bright. And so, when you build stencils for, for, like, squeegeeing solder paste onto a surface mount.
Daz: board.
Daz: You have to have these little voids, and you squeegee over the voids, and the way that that's typically done is they do this, like, photo thing, and then drop acid on it, and it eats in from both sides, and you end up with something that looks like an hourglass, and then you squeegee through the hourglass, and the middle of the hourglass.
Daz: Causes, like, volume problems, because sometimes it takes the top half
Daz: back up with it. And he's like, hey, if we shoot it from a laser and we make it more like a trapezoid… So anyway.
Daz: Cutting this to a much shorter conversation, while I was in school, I programmed the thing, bought a bunch of, like, various different kind of nickel-encoded steel for the… which is what they use for the stencils, because they have to be squeegeed a bunch, and started firing at steel with this laser and trying to figure things out with microscopes… Do you know that steel is reflective?
Daz: Yeah, yeah, and I had the goggles on, like Back to the Future. Anyway, did all that stuff, and then quickly realized that Nidium Yag is not the right type of laser to drill steel.
Daz: and told him that I, like, unfortunately, I filled this out, and he's like, oh, that's okay, I kind of thought this might go sideways, so I already talked to Texas State Technical College, and I had an independent appraiser come in and appraise the laser, and with the tax write-off I'm going to get from donating it to the college, I'm going to end up making, like, $40,000, and that was plenty to pay you part-time to figure out if we could actually turn this into a business. And so he donated it off.
Daz: And then he's like, oh, by the way, I've decided I want to sell this other business, because it's taking a lot of my time, and I want to go fishing.
Daz: Will you come… will you come computerize the business and run it for me? And then I'll tell them that you're the general manager, and they don't need me, and I'll sell the business, and you can run it. And I said…
Daz: I said, okay. And so I did that.
GM: Wait a second, wait a second, wait a second, you did not work at a startup, and yet had several quintessential Silicon Valley startup stories.
Daz: Awesome.
GM: Like, I mean, all I'm waiting for here and now is to find out that there was a safe, you know,
Daz: So anyway, took that job, ran the comp- computerized the company, this is Windows for Workgroups 311, and nettastic over 9,600 bod modems. I'm just dating myself. Computerized it, got all this going.
Daz: Ran the business, they… he did, true to his word, sold the business. The new guys came in, my… they were… this is back when investment banking firms would, like, buy up a bunch of mom-and-pops that were the same, and then try to package them and IPO them, and… and profit.
Thorin: Private equity, okay, yeah.
Daz: Yeah, this is before they were private equity. Anyway, so, I did all that. They loved the way I was running mine, so then I ended up running all of operations, like, west of the Mississippi, and hated it, because I wanted to do nerd stuff.
Daz: And, like, I had all these factory workers, and, like, I was like, no! So I took, like, a 70% pay cut and went to become a contractor for the Air Force Information Warfare Center, because hacking sounded cool, and I wanted to go do that. Moved to San Antonio, and restarted my career.
Daz: Met a bunch of people, some of which were the people that founded, Wheel Group, which was an IDS that got acquired by, A'lai. So then when I wanted to move back to Austin, I called some of them, and they're like, yeah, you can come work for A'lai. And then I went to A'lai, Juniper, VMware, back to A'lai.
Grygum: Oh, that's funny. Did you know Justin Pettit? I think he might have worked for William. Yeah, I knew Justin. Yeah, yeah, you knew Justin, okay, yeah.
Grygum: he was…
Thorin: But this is why I tell people when they're, like, early in their career, I'm like, if all you do is chase money, you're gonna end up in a place that you hate, right? At some point, you gotta figure out what do you want to do, because, like, that job that you landed in sounds like one of those jobs where I'm sure it could pay well, and it's pure hell.
Daz: Yeah, it paid amazingly well for a…
Daz: what was I, the 22-year-old or something? Because I went to school early. Like, I graduated…
Daz: I was… yeah, I was… so I'd have been 22. Yeah, I was 22, and I had that job.
Daz: I mean…
GM: I just remembered I have to send a note to Mark Johnson to tell him that he's not the only high school dropout I knew at VMware.
GM: This is a rubbing gag.
Daz: He doesn't want everybody to know, GM.
GM: I won't tell him. I won't tell him.
GM: Hold on! I will tell him that he was not… actually, I'll even make it worse, he was not the only distinguished engineer who was a high school dropout.
Zalthir: True?
Daz: I find that a lot of people who are very bright get very bored with high school very easily. I may have actually dropped out of high school if I hadn't found this… Texas had this program where you could
Daz: Do your junior and your senior year of high school at university.
Daz: And so my high school diploma is from the University of North Texas.
Zalthir: Oh, that's cool.
GM: Alright, as much as I would enjoy having this conversation to the wee hours of the morning, I think… and as much as I feel my son would then say that we're like that episode of The Simpsons…
Daz: So, I have a question, though, before you get going.
GM: Shoot.
Daz: Have I worked at a startup?
GM: not a Silicon Valley venture-funded startup.
Daz: This is why I said no, but I kind of have a…
Thorin: And I haven't worked at a startup either.
GM: Yeah, you did, you worked at Heptio.
Thorin: Yeah, we were not a Silicon Valley company.
GM: It was a… it's a… you know, but if you read the thing I wrote.
Thorin: Silicon Valley's the state of mind.
GM: Valleys of mood, a coffee shop! A state of mind! A geography!
GM: Alright.
Daz: Sorry for the segue.
GM: No, dude, that was actually worth the price of admission.
GM: Alley… okay, so, just to remind you what happened, Alley…
GM: Good morning. Well, they told the surviving thug to ignore the cleric and go after Daz, shouting that the wizard had the key, though in truth, Grygum quietly held both the key and the gem. Daz conjured a massive explosion of fireball… of fire that engulfed the surviving thug.
GM: And the successful detonation sent shockwaves of a different kind through all of Candlekeep. Bells rang, screams echoed, and scholars scrambled for their notebooks, because the fireball's very existence proved that the library's legendary magical wards had been broken.
GM: A'lai, and, you know, papers had to be written. A'lai killed the wounded thug himself, and then, hands trembling, proposed a surrender. He revealed he knew the location of a secret room beneath the keep, the two lines of a cryptogram that mattered, and the name of a finger in Menzoberranzan, paying to keep a certain drow breathing.
GM: He begged not for free… freedom, but for a cell inside Candlekeep's magic-nullifying prison.
GM: The one place he believed he might survive what was coming. Grygum used restorative magic to bring Zalthir back to conscience, and the party began to consider the wizard's offer. Before they could act, his entire assassin appeared. A'lai's hands bowed, looked at the newcomer, and said coolly, Took your time! I've been in the room. I know exactly who is carrying what.
GM: He nodded towards Daz. The assassin launched a brutal assault, striking Daz again and again until the wizard crumpled unconscious of the floor. The assassin then searched Daz's body for the sapphire and found nothing, his horror plain on his face.
GM: For the gem had long since passed to Grygum. Thorin's fury was immediate and absolute. He struck the assassin with a menacing blow that filled the man with dread, then unleashed a relentless fury of attacks, flurry of attacks, including a devastating radiant strike that left the assassin crumpled and broken on the high tower floor.
GM: Grygum rushed to Daz and poured healing energy into him, pulling him back from the edge of death, while A'lai Aivenmore looked on in tearful panic, his last hope of rescue lying unconscious at his feet.
GM: The party secured A'lai and stripped his high tower key from him, taking care to not bring the two keys together. Well, Thorin quietly slipped the key of Zalthir…
Grygum: What happens if you bring the two keys together?
GM: No, no, that was a typo. Grygum quietly slipped the key to Zalthir, and it was ultimately tucked away inside Glabbagool for safekeeping, the gelatinous cube standing just a little bit taller with pride at the responsibility.
Grygum: It's a little weird to store things inside our NPCs, but I'll allow it.
GM: Yeah, sensing that remaining in the room would be catastrophic, the party moved A'lai out of the high tower lobby, a decision that proved wise moments later, when Manshoon himself arrived. The legendary wizard conjured a wall of force and shattered the magical door that the two keys were meant to protect.
GM: Breaking Candlekeep's inner sanctum through sheer, overwhelming power. He had arrived alone and visibly weakened, having expended enormous magical resources to get here.
GM: But he had arrived, and A'lai, trembling in the party's custody, revealed the one card he still held. He had never told Manshoon the truth about what lay inside the depository. That secret, and whatever A'lai intended to trade for, would have to wait.
GM: For now.
GM: Alright.
GM: Okay, so there's this insanely powerful wizard hiding behind a wall of force, broke… has broken into the, secret room.
GM: And,
Thorin: blue.
GM: Alright.
GM: So, the way we're gonna do this is we're actually gonna use a spreadsheet.
GM: No, we're not gonna…
Thorin: It's not DnD unless you have spreadsheets.
Thorin: Looking at, like, who's the Babushka woman there? Is that…
GM: We're…
Thorin: on the map.
Grygum: Oh.
GM: I, like… Do I have the wrong map?
Zalthir: Oh, that's great. The Bushka woman. Yeah?
Thorin: I'd, like, hover over some… so the assassin and thug are done.
Thorin: Who's out there, Thorin, Grygum, I can't… I don't see anything for Glabbagool or for Daz.
Grygum: I mean, this is the map we were using.
Thorin: No, I'm just saying when I hover, it's just like…
Grygum: Yeah, I don't know who that is either.
GM: Let me just see.
Zalthir: It's a great icon.
Grygum: Yes.
GM: Murmo.
GM: No, I wasn't… I just… I don't know.
Zalthir: Oh, she's gone.
Grygum: Oh, okay. Yeah, I remember this one now, too.
GM: Alright, okay, the babushka.
GM: No, that was something else, it's another map. Alright.
GM: So, I lay Aivenmore.
GM: Is here?
Grygum: They're all just so elaborate and carefully designed that, you know, it's… sometimes I can't tell which one we should be on.
GM: Are you making fun of my scrolls?
Grygum: Hey, mine would be just as bad.
GM: Alright, okay, there we go, there we are. That, this is the High Tower, the Wall of Force is, let me just do this…
GM: Extra large.
GM: There is a wall of force, and it is sufficiently large such that all of Zalthir's mathematics will be proven to be insufficient, and he should not spend time trying to…
GM: Trying to carefully point out how I got the line wrong.
Zalthir: That sounds like a challenge.
GM: No, no, no, I'm simply stating that anything I've done…
GM: This person over here is Tadric, sorry.
GM: That's who that is.
GM: That's who the Babushka woman is.
GM: There we go.
GM: Okay, so, Manshoon shows up, and, just to make this a little bit interesting.
GM: The way this will work, just to create a sense of urgency.
GM: Because I'm told that's a great management technique.
GM: Alright.
GM: Alright, so imagine there's… there's a… so there's something that's gonna happen. Depending on the actions you take.
GM: the,
GM: whoever gets… the… the… if you can… you will either intersect with Manshoon, or he will… and be able to stop him, or,
GM: he will… He will get what he's… he will get what he came for, so…
GM: Here. Imagine there is a… imagine there is, six boxes. I am not going to draw this, because… wait, there's a spreadsheet. We do have a spreadsheet.
GM: I'm like, I just realized we do, in fact, have a spreadsheet. But for the purposes of this exercise, let's just imagine Manshoon is… there are 6 boxes.
GM: Manshoon.
GM: Here's on box 1.
GM: You party on box zero.
GM: And soon.
GM: That's 2 box 6.
GM: He wins.
GM: Alright.
GM: Just imagine… what?
Grygum: How should I imagine these boxes? Are they…
GM: Or they just suggest that, no, no, there are things that can happen, so your goal is to figure out what he's up to, and stop him before he gets it.
Grygum: Okay.
GM: Right? And there are multiple ways to stop him, including killing him.
Grygum: Always a popular way.
GM: And depending on which paths you take, you may or may not meet him before the end.
Daz: Okay.
GM: And because this is this party, I have no contingency plan, so if you do something completely off the rails, it may involve me going back to my drawing board and going, hmm, and doing re… and pulling off one of my DnD books, you know, which will make me very happy, but it might cause a pause in the game.
GM: I would be delighted if you did that, so just to be clear, this would be awesome if you guys did something completely unexpected, but I just want you to be aware that it might take me a moment to jump back onto the scene.
GM: Hurry!
GM: Okay, so you're now sitting with A'lai.
GM: Alright.
Grygum: So… Okay.
GM: A'lai goes, he's not looking for me! That's the part you don't understand! He has… he's… he sent a courier 11 years, and the courier wear a glove, and I never saw the face, and I told myself that was discretion.
GM: It was not discretion, it was that I wasn't worth a face!
GM: Basically, he's discovered that he's been a patsy this whole time. He thought he was an important person. He literally thought that Manshoon was gonna show up to kill him. He thought the assassin was coming for that, and now he's realized he's been a patsy. The whole time, he's been a patsy.
Grygum: even worth killing.
GM: No, it's not even worth killing. Like, Manshoon shows up and doesn't even waste the time to kill him.
Grygum: Not worth the price of the bullet.
GM: Right, exactly. So this is, you know, his ego, his entire…
Grygum: spell slot.
GM: He wasn't, yes, not worth the spell slot. He wasn't… not worth the straight, okay, so…
GM: So, what is it? So… so he's like, here's what I want.
GM: I, I want, I want, I want, I want to be put in the prison of the, I want you to take me and put me in the null magic prism of Candlekeep. It's the only thing that'll keep me alive.
Grygum: Well, before we can do that, we're going to need your help with Manshoon and how we can find him and stop him.
GM: Right, just to remind you, he, what did… what was his offer last week? I just gotta remember myself.
Grygum: Because without some help, I have no fucking clue.
GM: Right, so, he meant… what A'lai offered
GM: Just check that, give me a second, I have this written down.
GM: Shrunk this little tiny carameless, and…
GM: So…
GM: So, what Manshoon… what he offered… he's offering a bunch of things, but things that he's offer… things that he offered to you guys that you may have forgotten, because, of course, you're… you do not have the privilege of sitting in front of all of these notes that I have.
GM: is that he claims to know who Daz is related to, the secret… you have the suspicion that he know about who Daz is really after, right?
Grygum: who's really after Daz?
GM: Yeah, who's really after… who's the person… Oh, who's really…
Daz: after me.
GM: Yeah, like, why is Daz still alive?
GM: Right? Like, who paid for these very expensive people to keep you alive?
GM: Right? That's one thing he might know. The second thing he might know, the second thing he says he knows is the real reason why, Manshoon showed up here.
GM: What's…
GM: And he knows some… he knows… he knows what… and so he knows those two things.
GM: Alright.
GM: He's willing to trade.
Grygum: Well, the one.
GM: I mean, and you know, but just to be clear, Tadric's there, so if you want to hand him over to Tadric, Tadric can take him into custody. If you tie his hands up and shove a sock in his mouth, he can't cast any spells anyway.
Grygum: Well, the one thing might be important to Daz, but I think knowing what Manshoon is up to is more important for the goal of the adventure here.
Grygum: He wants this in exchange for basically not being tortured and killed.
GM: Very specifically, he, he…
Grygum: And he wants to be put into the prison.
GM: Right, and the most important thing he wants is to be put into the prison, because the most important thing he wants is to…
GM: characters. We're in the process of rolling the new characters, so… Don't be so loud. Okay.
GM: So, he… the thing that he… the thing that he wants is… so, as you recall, at the very beginning of this adventure.
GM: When you wanted to put little drow in prison?
GM: Candlekeep has got null magic prisms.
GM: So, A'lai Aivenmore thinks the safest place in the… in the… in the… on Toril, and in the north, is inside of one of those null magic prisms.
Grygum: Because nobody else can use the, the magic there either, and so he'd be safe from it.
GM: Yes, and so if you're trying to protect yourself against a powerful wizard, that feels like the safest place in all of creation.
Grygum: I, won't mention to him that, that failed here.
GM: No, this is… this is not the time… you can, I'm just saying.
Grygum: Right, it's just the wrong time to mention it.
GM: Right.
GM: So, so that's what he wants.
GM: Tadric…
Grygum: I'm… I'm willing to say that. There's no skin off,
GM: Right.
Grygum: me.
GM: Alright, Rest of you?
GM: Now, do you want to give that to him? He's, by the way, he's, what do you want to give it in exchange for?
Grygum: Well, we definitely need to know everything that he knows about, Manshoon. Daz, do you want to ask for your,
Daz: Yeah, if he has any, clue on who is funding both the protection and the
Daz: The… trying to keep me alive, and the folks that are trying to keep me unalive.
GM: So, you want both of those pieces.
Daz: If he knows them, like, I don't know what he knows. I think every little bit of information we get right now helps draw a picture of the puzzle.
GM: I see.
Grygum: I mean, what do we have to offer,
Grygum: Besides what he's already asked for.
GM: Right,
GM: He looks at you and says, what guarantees will I have that I will be placed in the Null so?
GM: like,
Grygum: Can, can we just, I don't know, take them there and,
Thorin: Or we could just hand them over, I mean, like…
Thorin: Like, you know… like, he's not in the position to negotiate.
GM: his…
Thorin: Fight.
GM: No, he's not, but he's an academic, so there's a… there's another officer there. You could tell Tadric, you can talk to Tadric, encourage Tadric to do it. I mean, he's… you don't have to take him there, you can…
Grygum: Alright, Tadric, this is how this has gotta be. We need to defeat Manshoon, or the entire tower is at risk.
Grygum: That this, we're in a hurry here, and we've got to make compromises that we otherwise might not want to make.
GM: Tadric is, like, that is a… Tadric realizes that, you know, you have been deputized by Kalan Strongbranch, and you have defeated, Moziqodo, saved his life,
Grygum: and I founded an entire new philosophy.
GM: He pauses.
Grygum: or something.
GM: Do… do I… do I… will we write a monograph… do a graph together?
Grygum: Yes, yes, we can do a two-person paper. It seems like I've got enough prestige here that it'll likely be accepted, so…
Grygum: But you never know with the whole anonymous submission thing, but I've got a pretty good track record.
GM: So, that was very well delivered. Tadric is…
GM: Like, I think I could have poked you in the middle of the night, and you would have delivered that.
Grygum: I've been on program committees before.
GM: That was very well delivered. Tadric signs off… Tadric is relieved, very pleased, sorry. He then… so Manshoon… sorry. A'lai is finally relieved. He's like, this is…
Grygum: And yeah, that is something I could mumble into my pillow, it's…
GM: Yeah, yeah, he has that look on his face of somebody who's been… who realizes that his whole… he thought he was the kingpin, he thought he was the man, but now he realized he was just a pawn in other people's plans.
GM: And so, he tells you that there is a secret room beneath the keep.
GM: Which everybody didn't know about, that holds a bunch of artifacts of extraordinary power.
GM: And that the way to them is by solving a cryptogram, And…
GM: He informs you that he knows two of the solutions to the cryptogram, because that's what… some research that he had been doing on his own.
GM: Once you go into the room, the nature of the cryptogram will be obvious.
GM: Finally, to your question, Baz, he goes.
GM: He goes, I could not trace the payments.
GM: I could only trace the patience.
GM: He goes 11 years.
GM: All these years I've been doing this work, and never once a demand, nobody is that patient who is not that safe. He pauses. There is one house in Menzoberranzan that can be… can afford to be patient. Baenre. It must be Baenre. No one else can afford to wait that long for nothing.
GM: So…
Daz: Okay.
GM: How's bad… how's… just in case you're wondering…
Daz: Right?
GM: I'll just drop that into the, oneNote.
GM: Sorry, the… So…
Thorin: Which channel did it end up in?
GM: The, okay, here we go. Roll 20 chat. If you see me sort of, like.
Thorin: 20 chat. I'm sorry, that was the one I wasn't looking at.
GM: Yeah.
GM: I mean, you know, I gotta say this. As a former Google employee, you should be comfortable with having 3 incompatible chats going.
Thorin: I mean, I wrote two of them.
GM: You should be, you should, this should be, this should be…
Thorin: You feel right at home.
GM: Yeah, right, I just, you know, I couldn't resist, man, sorry. Okay, Tadric,
GM: Alright, Tadric, Tadric says, I will take… I will take her… I will take him to the prison.
GM: Right.
GM: And so it marches them off.
GM: Okay. So… Alright.
Grygum: Alright, everyone got what they wanted.
GM: Yes, everybody did get what they wanted.
Grygum: What did we learn?
GM: Let's see, there's one more thing.
GM: Hold on.
GM: So, what you learned was that Manshoon
GM: has been trying to get into Candlekeep to steal something of extraordinary value in a room that nobody knew existed.
GM: That held things that nobody knew about.
Grygum: Boy, he could have totally gotten away with it, since, you know, nobody knew it was there, so they wouldn't have missed it.
GM: Yes, the problem was that to get there, you needed.
Grygum: If it hadn't been for us damn kids.
GM: Yes, exact… did I say that?
GM: What?
Zalthir: meddling kid, yes.
GM: You meddling kids!
GM: Alright, hold on.
GM: Alright.
GM: Right.
GM: Okay, so it consists of a set of questions that
GM: This consists of a set of questions.
GM: Darn.
GM: There we go, there we go.
GM: Right.
GM: So… And so…
GM: What… what he explains, what he explains is that there's a set of questions inside… there were a set of questions inside of the secret room that…
GM: provide… that guarded the Vault of Secrets.
GM: And the questions themselves…
Thorin: Theselves are secret.
GM: Well, like, as with everything in Candlekeep, secret is a complicated word.
GM: Right? Secret, but not secret, you know, that kind of thing.
GM: So let me just do this.
Grygum: The levels of classification are extremely vague.
GM: Yes.
GM: And so he was able to find the answers to two of those. He was able to find two of those questions.
GM: And the answers to two of those questions. And the whole idea behind this is that if you didn't have
GM: If you couldn't answer the question, you couldn't get the clues that would lead you to the secret room.
GM: Right? And so, that was… and so that the idea was that nobody would ever be able to do that.
Grygum: Does it have anything to do with the airspeed velocity of a laden swallow?
GM: No, no, it does not. It does not.
GM: I'm prepared.
Grygum: I'm prepared for those.
GM: Yeah, but just for the record, he explains that, no, it doesn't, but why would you ask?
GM: It's very odd… I mean, he's very confused.
Grygum: It's an old folk tale.
GM: He then, he then looks at you even more confused, explaining that A'lai looks at you more confused, explaining that that… that makes no sense, because, you know.
GM: The whole purpose of this… Okay, hold on.
GM: Cancel.
GM: Remote. I mean, I'm sorry.
Grygum: Don't worry about it, it's magic.
GM: He's a very powerful wizard. He does not find your humor funny.
Grygum: Some of these academics, you know.
GM: Yes, I know, it's like, just because… just because I'm your prisoner does not mean I am a fool.
GM: Alright.
GM: Alright, so this is what you find.
GM: So apparently, what you learn is that, if with the… with these… this information.
GM: You can find the entrance to the Vault of Secrets.
Grygum: Oh.
GM: With.
Grygum: It popped up.
Thorin: Okay.
Grygum: No.
Thorin: Why do we want to find the entrance to the Vault of Secrets?
Thorin: Do we want to scale.
Grygum: it before Manshoon does.
Thorin: Okay, so is the…
GM: It's true.
Thorin: race to that, or do we want to stop machine, or like, you know, I'm just saying, like, I don't give a shit what's in there, I just want to get on with my day, you know what I'm saying? Like…
Daz: If we take the thing that he wanted from there, then maybe it stops his grand plan?
Thorin: Then he'll come after us.
Daz: That's fine, then we can, like, convince them to join us, or, you know, kill them, or whatever.
Thorin: He said, well, we could do that now!
GM: The problem is you don.
Daz: We don't know where he's at.
Thorin: Oh, okay, so it's a matter of, we don't know where he's at, he's escaped, so everybody's racing to get to this thing, and so, okay.
Grygum: Yep. So,
Thorin: Hand me the idol. Yeah.
GM: Right, yeah, so…
Grygum: Lay said that he'd solve 3 of them, right?
GM: Two of them, two of them.
Grygum: Two of them.
GM: Yep.
Grygum: The solutions would probably help.
GM: Yes, yes, yes, I was… let me get that. Sorry.
GM: Alright.
GM: So, he has the answer to number 3.
GM: Which is… Just make sure.
GM: Is this one?
GM: Hold on.
GM: Let me just make sure before I give you the wrong answer.
GM: Oh yes, and then there's a second page to the riddle. Sorry, that was the part I was missing.
GM: If you… Which is the other part. So the questions then, of course, as you know, how cryptograms work.
GM: Then get added.
GM: then feed into a document. If you're familiar with these puzzles, this should not be a surprise. If you're not.
Grygum: Is this a letter substitution cipher?
GM: Yeah, it's a latter sub… it's a latter substitution cipher.
GM: I need to…
Grygum: Like the ones that you used to find in newspapers, when news.
GM: Yeah.
GM: Yes.
GM: Alright, cipher a paragraph.
GM: I will not make you, go through all of this. I will provide the answer unless you… unless one of you really wants to do it, in which case I will patiently watch.
GM: I have done these things with people like you, and they've insisted on spending hours solving this, and I've done it with people like you who've said, no, I will not solve this right now. That is too much like my day job.
Grygum: You know, that's me on different days, honestly.
GM: Yeah, just in case. Alright, so he gives you the answer to…
Thorin: I'm having a hard time reading this font. So, the third one is YLFJ.
GM: So, the third one is… The, the basic, the base insult of a black knight.
Thorin: Right, yeah, but the letter is underneath it.
GM: Y-L-F-J-D-A-L-P-F.
Thorin: Okay, now the second to last one, is that letter an I or a J?
GM: That is a J.
Thorin: But that's a different symbol from the other J.
Grygum: Yeah, it is.
Thorin: There's… there's two J's. I'm gonna call that one an I.
GM: Yeah. Well, yeah, we can call that an I. That's probably…
Grygum: I guess it doesn't matter as long as you're consistent.
GM: Yes. In general, if you find all the answers, you will, I will just tell you what the answer is, unless you're really compelled to do the work.
GM: All right, or you could solve it before you do all the work, in which case, you know.
GM: Voila! Alright, so, the third one from the… the third one is the base insult of a Black Knight.
GM: Okay, I'll just make sure I don't… I do not trust this.
GM: Okay.
GM: Alright, so the BERT… okay, just double checking so that I didn't…
GM: You asked the last one, are you asking about the Js? Is that what you're saying?
Thorin: Yeah, I think… I think there's I's and J's, and they look very similar, I'm just saying.
GM: Yeah, those were eyes. Good guess.
GM: Nope, they were… camera?
Thorin: One of them's I's, one of them's J's, it doesn't matter as long as we're consistent.
GM: Yeah, okay. So, Fisti… okay, so here we are. Let me just say this is the first one. He goes… the answer to number… I'm putting it in the, Roll20 chat.
Grygum: This is the base insult of a black knight?
GM: Yes.
Grygum: That doesn't mean anything more to me than, Than what we'd started with.
GM: Alright, well, he goes, this… he goes, well, Alley just can't, like, you know, very… he feels very proud of himself.
GM: I stumbled upon this question, and he starts going on, in one of the books that I was told to extract.
GM: And it refers to a word that the creator magically enched centuries ago under the base of one of the oversized black marble chest pieces, which see plenty of use on the Philosopher's Court.
GM: What I noticed was that successive keepers of Tobed had ensured that the knight is never replaced.
Grygum: Okay.
GM: Right, so he goes, this is how I was… he was very… he's very smug about his achievement here.
Grygum: Congratulations!
GM: Thank you, thank you, I… I… I… I'm… I feel,
Grygum: Party popper emoji?
GM: party popper emoji?
GM: So then he says, as for the second clue, I was particularly proud of this one as well. He feels very compelled to narrate, as one does when one is being taken to a prison to escape a homicidal
GM: Creature that, you know, keeps coming back from the dead as a series of silmacrums.
GM: Here goes…
Grygum: We all have our habits. This is for the Eastern Light of Mystra's Mantle?
GM: No, this is for number 6.
Thorin: ABM, okay.
GM: Yes. The reply of Batbayar when you give him a hand.
GM: Alright.
GM: And he goes, what is that, does he explain this when he goes.
Grygum: I hope it's a word I know this time.
GM: Well, he goes, well, he goes, that one was easy. Bo.
GM: Kbm, yes, Bo. He goes, well, this, of course, is,
Grygum: E-O-W? Yeah.
GM: Yes.
Grygum: So, okay, he… he bows to you?
GM: Yes, yes, well, yes, exactly! Sorry, he is… he goes, exactly!
Grygum: Oh, is he, like, a performer, and you're…
GM: Yeah, we… Whoa!
GM: He goes, Batbayar is a legendary halfling bar whose statue dominates the entry hall of the School of the Drama Library.
GM: And so one day, when I was late at night, I applauded the statue. I don't remember what the reason was. I think I may have read a fascinating article about his work once.
GM: And I felt compelled to congratulate him in that moment. It came to loud, and Dao bowed deeply from the waist in acknowledgement of my applause.
Grygum: Oh, so you, you, you've actually… Tested this.
GM: Yes, yes, yes. It was, I was, it was, yes, I was very pleased with myself. He goes, see, this demonstrates, he pauses and goes, this is what you acquire after a lifetime of serving the institution of Candlekeep.
Grygum: Well, congratulations!
GM: Yeah, so you got… you see… and this is why I… I have nothing but my relationship to this institution. Tadric then says, are we done, A'lai? He goes.
GM: I suppose.
Grygum: One more.
Thorin: What was the answer to the… the base insult of a Black Knight?
GM: I put it.
Daz: In the chat.
Thorin: Oh, okay.
Grygum: Fustilugs.
GM: For still works.
Grygum: He only has 2?
GM: Yes.
Grygum: Oh, well, send him off to the jail then. I'm done with it.
GM: Yes? Yeah, you're done with this guy, he's… You're done with him. Alright.
GM: Tadric, so you now have these other clues.
GM: So, while you're pondering these clues, hey,
GM: Let's see… it's trying to figure out what the hell you're supposed to do with all of this stuff.
Thorin: I'm using this site where you can type in letters, and it actually fills it all out so that you can…
Grygum: Oh, I'm not sure.
Thorin: But, like… Smart.
GM: Okay, that's fair, that's fair.
Thorin: It just helps me keep track of stuff. And I assume that the… oh, wait, this is a… There's more text.
GM: Yes.
Thorin: Oh, and I see, so once we do this, we'll understand.
GM: Yes, hold on. Exactly.
GM: Alright.
GM: Okay.
GM: So, as you're staring at these, notes.
GM: Wondering what… as you're staring at… when A'lai hears about this, he says, I think I can help you, but we need to… but I suggest we go to the investigator's office, where we can put these… these notes on the floor and bring all of our best minds to see what we can do.
Grygum: Good idea.
GM: So, he, marked… he… conveniently, the investigator's office is near the prison, so you head off to the investigator's office, and, he pulls, and so, you know, the questions have been transcribed.
GM: Fortunately, A'lai has photographic memory, so this information is accessible to you.
GM: Alright.
GM: As you're sitting there going off, trying to figure this out, Sylvira herself arrives.
GM: Just as a side note.
GM: She is, she is the mother of Moziqodo, whom you guys killed, so, you know…
GM: You're beautiful.
Grygum: I'm sure she doesn't mind.
GM: What? She doesn't know this yet. She doesn't know that her son's dead.
GM: She's… she's very… she sees you, she's grateful to see you, she notices, Thorin.
GM: Thanks, Hugh, for saving, Tadric.
Thorin: I do what I can for those that I can.
GM: Yeah.
GM: Wow, that was cold.
Thorin: I just… I'm not ready to… I'm not ready to cop to what we did.
GM: Just, I'm just, just okay.
GM: Alright. Alright, so, she says… she's like, she looks at Daz.
GM: And is, very happy. She, she says, you know,
GM: She's very happy to, you know, she's turned… she said, thanks, Daz, and thanks you for what you've done, and says that this has been a tragedy of upper proportions with so many of the chief avowed, dead.
GM: Right? And says… looks over the list and starts to laugh as she reads the information, and reminds herself of… says, well, these… these are too… these are almost too easy.
Daz: The riddle, you mean? She's, like…
GM: Yeah, she's reading the riddle, and she… because she goes…
GM: So the first… no, not the read, the questions.
Daz: Oh.
GM: He goes, the true name of she who serves in spirit. How could one not know about this?
GM: The clue refers to Miirym, the Sentinel Wyrm.
Thorin: Wait.
Daz: I'm doing.
Thorin: the window, where did it go?
Thorin: How does it… Oh, this is, like… Okay, sorry.
Thorin: I'll figure this out.
Thorin: F, okay.
GM: Miirym. Miirym, is a dragon.
GM: This is a dragon that lives in the castle.
GM: And and of course, I happen to know her true name. It was a conversation we once had about demonic possession and the importance of true names.
GM: For those of you who don't know, the way you can secure power over a dragon… of a demonic power is by… by giving them… by having their true name. And so she goes, here, here's the true name.
GM: That's the answer to number 1.
Daz: Correct.
GM: And then Sylvira Savikas, again, since you guys did not attack her, did not do anything terrible to her, she's actually, you know, feeling that it's her job to help Candlekeep in this moment of crisis, and since she's too weak to do it herself.
GM: From her illness.
GM: Okay, so she then, she says, for clue number 2… She says…
GM: The Eastern Light of Mystra's Mantle… Mantle.
GM: And she goes, yes, this one, again, a trivial, trivial, trivial question, almost too easy to answer. And she explains that, this is an obscure, a rather obscure constellation.
GM: which refers to its easternmost star, which can be looked up on the star charts in the Orrery of the Astronomicon, which I happen to walk by.
GM: And as she says that,
GM: That when I went past the astronomicron, there were 3 people in it who did not work there.
GM: Which, you know, could be 3 members of the Avowed doing research, or, somebody fighting.
GM: Alright.
GM: She said, with that, you've earned…
GM: Okay, so, so that leaves you with the two, two more left.
GM: So, does anybody roll an intelligence or performance check?
Thorin: I'm solving this, give me a second here, I had to type everything in.
Grygum: Yeah, I'm looking at it, too.
GM: Okay.
GM: I see you guys are going to try to solve it the hard way.
Thorin: Well, this is…
GM: This is you guys.
Thorin: Bo.
GM: Let me just make sure on the… I just… since you are going to try to solve it the hard way, let me just see if I… let me just see whether that was an I or a J.
Thorin: Doesn't matter.
Daz: Oh my god.
GM: doesn't… But, I mean, I feel like I should at least…
Thorin: Okay, so VY…
GM: Was it the first one?
GM: Oh my, oh my god.
Thorin: I…
GM: I just need to… I need to do… my OCD's kicking in, so let me get my OCD out of the way. The J in Black Knight was actually…
GM: an I.
Thorin: Okay. Feed the quill of something the same… okay.
Thorin: So, I'll show you…
GM: Turns out that Thorin learned a game when he was playing with the Giants. That's how he learned Giant.
Thorin: Okay, this is what I have, because I'm pretty sure that the JBJCS is to the…
Thorin: And so everything fells out, but those well reversed and is versed.
Thorin: Probably in…
Thorin: Guardian, last.
GM: While you're at it, roll a, intelligence check.
Thorin: To all of us?
GM: anybody, either roll 4 intelligence checks, or somebody roll with Advantage.
Grygum: I'm busy trying to decipher this.
Daz: An intelligence check, you said?
GM: Performance.
Daz: I only have a plus zero. All of us do it, or is somebody else doing it with advantage?
GM: That's your call.
Thorin: Alright, so I'm putting this in Discord.
Daz: Who has a… who has a plus on performance?
Thorin: Alright.
Zalthir: Maybe Glabbagool?
GM: Glabbagool is, you know, all about the Zen.
Daz: I mean, I guess I can roll it with advantage if no one has better than a… better than me.
GM: Grygum said.
Daz: zero.
GM: Grygum, do you have a… what's your… what's your performance?
Grygum: Performance. Performance. Performance plus 2, yeah.
GM: Alright, you should probably roll it with Advantage.
Zalthir: Yeah, we're all helping, cheering you on.
Thorin: Alright, I decoded the whole thing.
Thorin: Feed the quill of Alaundo the Seer.
Thorin: Tread as many steps as he lived in years. Sprinkle dust of Mechanus on dormant gears.
Grygum: I think you missed a… I think you missed a line.
Thorin: Did I?
Grygum: I see a line beginning with utter, the original, Prophecy.
Thorin: Well, this is what I got, in case you.
Grygum: Oh, okay, go on.
Thorin: That's my latest, so feed the…
Thorin: One last guardia of knowledge remains to verify the chosen readers
Thorin: Lambs, but those well-versed in Candlekeep's lore may fearlessly pass the obsidian door.
GM: Alright.
Thorin: I think that's it. I don't know.
Thorin: I could be wrong.
Thorin: Claims. Oh, I got a J and a… see, the claims is claims, so that's a T… that's a claim.
GM: All right, okay. Well, that was very impressive. You did actually… I mean, that was very impressive.
Thorin: I consider that a cheat, because I could have done all that by hand. I didn't like…
GM: I'm with you, I'm just trying to think, like, how would… how would they… how would the academic lights in that room handle the idea of the…
GM: dwarven, like.
Thorin: I did fit… I did miss one, yeah.
GM: The dwarven… the dwarf and the… the,
GM: I'm Grygum solving this. I think, for a moment here, this becomes a part of the endless debate of the great question of our age.
Grygum: Haha.
GM: I mean, you know, this will… this will, this will truly become, you know, how first, dwarf…
GM: solves a dwarf convinces Protanther, and now another dwarf
GM: Solves a riddle that protects an ancient artifact.
Grygum: I have pretty much the same thing here, too.
GM: Yes, it is.
Thorin: How'd you get there, Grygum?
Grygum: I think I might have mixed up one or two letters, but it.
Thorin: Yeah, the I and the J.
Grygum: That's yours.
Thorin: As long as you're consistent, but…
GM: just for the record, as a dyslexic, I'm very impressed that you guys got through this at all.
Daz: Fantastic.
Grygum: This website that he found is a little eccentric, but works well enough.
Thorin: I mean, I did a search for cryptogram sort of solver, and a lot of them try to look at dictionaries and solve it for you. I'm like, clearly there's gonna be random-ass words like…
Grygum: Yeah, Alaundo.
GM: Alright.
Daz: You'd pick quilt.
GM: Yes.
Grygum: Yeah, so the line that you missed, I think, says, Utter the original prophecy to unseen ears.
Thorin: Okay, that rhymes with years and years and.
GM: Alright. See you. Okay. So, okay, so you guys solved it. Well done. This is actually good.
Grygum: The hardest part was trying to type in all of the original while still trying to listen.
GM: Alright.
GM: Okay, so…
Thorin: I'm sorry you had this big thing, I'm like, oh, I solved it.
GM: Not a big deal.
GM: Okay.
Thorin: I mean, we still need the dust of methane to know How long…
Grygum: No.
Thorin: Alaundo lived, the seer lived, and…
Grygum: Yeah, are we supposed to learn something important from this, or was it just a puzzle?
GM: It's just a puzzle. Alright. No, no, no, no, you were supposed to learn something important from it. I'm just giving.
Grygum: Oh, well, now I have to try to interpret it.
GM: Oh, no, no, so, so you…
GM: Okay, you've got quite a bit of…
GM: Alright.
GM: Okay, so…
GM: All right, so, alright, okay, good, I just… what I wanted to know. Okay, so while you're… while you're having this… needed to keep everything in track, lots of things to keep in track. All right, so,
GM: Fortunately, you're in a room full of… with Sylvira, and at that point in time, Kalan Strongbranch arrives, huffing and puffing, explaining that he has the answer to clue number 5.
Grygum: Wait, sorry, we already solved it.
GM: Again, there's a moment of stunned silence, but he recovers… he goes… and he pauses and goes, yes, well, I'm relieved to see that, I'm relieved to see that.
GM: Bleh.
Grygum: And that was one that all I knew anyway, that was Beau.
GM: Oh.
GM: He pauses. Anyway, fortunately, he arrives just in time to, read the thing and realizes what the, what this is referring to. He goes, as a member of the, guards, I've walked these grounds many times and am very familiar with all of the points of interest.
GM: He's standing there looking for someone to acknowledge him, you know.
Grygum: Good, excellent.
GM: Yeah, you know, he wants to feel that he's participating, he's adding his two cents, he's that executive who shows up at the meeting and has nothing useful to say, and wants everybody to, like, acknowledge their uselessness.
Grygum: Oh, yeah, that's the sort of person you put in charge of, you know, the…
Grygum: Convening speech, and tell them to keep it at 10 minutes.
GM: Yes, and, and, you know, that security in a wizard's tower that never needed security. Alright, he then explains that the first line of the riddle is instructing you to locate the statue of Alaundo.
Grygum: Is this the thing that's in the basement and nobody knew about it?
Daz: Hmm…
GM: The House of Alaundo stands in the middle of Founder's Court. Oh.
Grygum: It is not a… okay, we do know about it.
GM: Yes, the ground floor stretches to the top of the building, but there's a gallery that forms a mezzanine. The ground floor features a large brass statue of Alaundo.
GM: Just to remind you, Alaundo is the great seer whose prophecies were no longer being repeated.
Grygum: So some parts of this aren't a mystery.
GM: Yes. And then in…
Grygum: place.
GM: Yeah, so the ground floor features a large brass statue of Alaundo bearing a quilt and ink pot mounted upon a large…
GM: dais.
GM: Right.
GM: Common superstition states that if you touch the quill, you will write a well-critiqued piece.
GM: Of academia, and the brass on the tip is certainly well worn.
GM: I swear to God, that's what it says.
GM: Those of you who haven't done college in a while, you… the, you know, there's always something that you would scrub and get a good result on. All right.
GM: Okay.
GM: So, alright.
GM: So, you all, I presume, head towards the,
Grygum: Oh, we go to the statue.
GM: I presume, like, they all head to the statue, so…
Grygum: Okay, and then it says, tried as many steps as he lived.
GM: Well, no, it says we have to feed the quill.
GM: So, there's an ink pot, there's a quill.
Grygum: Oh, so… I guess we could…
Thorin: watch.
Grygum: You could interpret that as dip the quill in the quill?
GM: Well, the ink… the ink, you'd have to, like, move the arm, which, I mean, given this is… or the ink pot is empty.
GM: It's an empty container.
Grygum: Okay.
GM: So…
GM: If you want to roll, just tell me. But imagine a statue of a man.
Grygum: Yeah, anybody have an idea what we should feed it, or…
Grygum: I mean, presumably ink.
Thorin: I'm guessing blood.
Grygum: Oh, it could be blood, yeah. What was… what was Alaundo… he was a seer, not a warrior, right?
GM: Right, right, he was, he was, he, you know… the…
GM: What is that name of that? Anostadamus of his age.
Grygum: Okay.
Grygum: Excuse me.
GM: Except his prophecies came out instead of the other one, who's also.
Grygum: It's worked. Okay.
GM: Yep, but, you know.
Zalthir: We don't do…
GM: Do you want to try ink?
Grygum: Let's start with ink.
Zalthir: What up?
Grygum: what?
Daz: I mean, there… there was the whole thing with the ink on the book, and it killed the guy.
GM: Yes.
Grygum: True.
Zalthir: I mean, we do… we did take a sample of the poisoned ink, we could try that.
Grygum: Oh, the poisoned ink!
Zalthir: Great question.
GM: But just to be clear, there's, like, a whole bunch of scholars, like, finding ink is not a problem.
Daz: Yeah, that's true.
Thorin: And also, finding blood's not a problem. We've got a bunch of scholars.
Grygum: Just, just tell them that the, the, the first, the, the, the first one to solve the riddle, gets their paper published.
GM: I think you might have not… then you might have too much blood.
Grygum: Yeah, that's true.
GM: Alright, does anyone… so, take it?
Grygum: I'm not actually evil, so I'm gonna start with ink. I ask this… I ask, around for…
GM: Right, so, you know, everybody starting… pulls out pouches of ink, right? Because, of course, like, you know, if you're a scholar, you…
GM: you know, there's… you pick Whitney, which one?
Grygum: Yeah, so I'll, I'll take, whatever looks freshest?
GM: Alright, so you pour it in.
GM: And then, you hear the grinding of stone as the statue slides forwards on its dais to reveal a long set of stairs leading down an unlit passage.
Grygum: This is cool.
Thorin: How long has the statue been here?
GM: Well, you really are gonna make me look this up.
Thorin: No, I'm just, like, a long time, right?
GM: Yes.
Thorin: And nobody over all that time has put ink in the ink well. I'm just saying. It's a little on the nose.
Grygum: I mean, maybe they haven't done it with intent.
Thorin: Okay.
GM: The minute you say that, they all kind of look at you in horror.
Thorin: Like, why would we deface the thing?
GM: Yes, yes, you know, there's, like, this…
Thorin: But wasn't, like, there's something else hidden in a statue earlier? I mean, like, we put stuff in statues, like, you know, little things all the time, right? I mean, like… Oh, go ahead. Okay, I'm not gonna…
GM: Yeah, he's, you know, they're all kind of, like, looking at you, like, this would, you know, Alaundo's like, no, apparently nobody.
Thorin: Alright, alright, alright, let's keep going.
GM: Alright, but you know, good plot hole, good plot hole discovery. Alright. Okay, so there's a bunch of stairs going down.
Grygum: How many, years did he live? It says we should go down that many steps.
GM: Everybody died, TPK. Well, thank you. My wife got me some food, so…
GM: Which is good, because I was getting really hungry. So, so it turns out nobody actually knows when he died, how old he was when he died.
GM: Okay. Awesome.
Grygum: well.
GM: Pause, pause, pause. Yeah. Because that's not considered important information. But fortunately, there is a copy of his
GM: biography.
Grygum: it's not listed on a statue? I mean…
GM: Certainly not.
Grygum: Pretty deficient to, plaque.
GM: Yeah, well, you know, it's one of those things.
GM: So…
GM: One of you can head over… you can all rush over to the House of Momentous Deeds.
GM: where the volume, Alaundo, the Wonder Years, has the answer, or you start going down the stairs and take your luck. What…
Grygum: I mean, I kind of eyeball it. Is it a long… very long staircase, or… I mean, does it just go down a.
Thorin: I'm afraid if we go one step too far, like, you know, I don't know, statues come alive and shit, right?
Grygum: Yeah, it'll… it'll kill us with a quill.
Thorin: Yeah.
Grygum: Yeah, let's go.
Thorin: Fighter than the sword.
GM: Alright.
GM: At this point in time, you've managed to acquire quite a retinue of feeble.
GM: Right? Scribbling notes, everybody, you know, discussing. You're apparently getting the impression that this will be studied for years.
GM: The part where Thorin solved the puzzle is what's causing everybody to be excited.
GM: And people are…
Grygum: I make a little speech explaining, so that, you know, at least some of it is likely to be written down correctly.
GM: Okay.
GM: Right.
GM: You find the book. Alright.
GM: The other option is to go to the… and of course, as you're going there, one of the… once somebody says, oh wait, I have a better solution! We could go to the grove, where every keeper of tomes is buried!
Thorin: Are we gonna dig him up and ask him?
GM: No, no, no, his date… his… how old he lived is written down there.
Thorin: Okay, yeah, that's a better idea.
GM: Alright, okay. So, off you head to the grove, and there you find his body and discover that he died at the age of 97.
Thorin: Alright, so 97 steps down the stairs, okay.
GM: Alright.
Thorin: Do we know… the original prophecy.
Thorin: I'm just saying, before we walk down 97 and then say, what's the prophecy, and they have to walk 97 back up, I'm just saying, that's a lot of stairs to walk.
GM: Well, so the good news is that every scholar in Castle Ward knows this one by heart, and since you've managed to make so many friends.
Daz: They'll let us know.
GM: They'll let you know. It also happens to be in,
GM: Yeah, so this is one of those things where you're able to pull it off, and thanks to all of your great work at helping people, and generally being supportive.
GM: There you have it. Okay.
Grygum: So, from knowledge of what scholars want, I make sure that everyone knows who lent me the ink.
GM: Alright.
Daz: I didn't.
GM: He makes sure that everybody knows the correct spelling of his name.
Grygum: Yeah.
Daz: He wants to get credit and citations?
GM: Sorry.
GM: Okay, so where do you want to stand when you… when you read the citation, when you read the prophecy?
Grygum: Oh.
Grygum: 97 seconds.
Thorin: steps down.
Grygum: Let's see. Tread as many steps as he lived in years, utter the original prophecy to unseen ears.
GM: Nope.
Grygum: Unseen ears.
Grygum: It could mean nothing in particular.
Zalthir: I mean, do we see anything of note, or just stand that many steps down?
GM: Yeah, I understand.
Grygum: Well, let's… let's go 97 steps down, and…
Grygum: Read the prophecy? Oh, do we… do we have the dust? We need dust. Dust of Mechanus.
GM: mechanism.
Grygum: Oh.
Thorin: 3. Yeah, that's one of those where I probably got the J and the K. This C.
Thorin: Yeah.
Thorin: Mechanus.
Grygum: You know, it says, those well-versed in Candlekeep's lore may fearlessly pass the obsidian door. Should… we don't actually know it that well? Who knows it best?
Zalthir: We have an entire entourage of scholars living in Candlekeep. Won't they all be.
GM: parts. Correct.
Grygum: Not all of them are experts on the… I'm sure there's some who know it better than others.
Grygum: Like, there must be a specialty in local history.
GM: I mean, you could ask and see who volunteers.
Grygum: Oh, yeah, yeah, I'm asking. Who are the experts on, the Candlekeep It.
GM: Okay, I just… I'm just imagining everybody raising their hand and screaming their qualifications.
GM: All right, to make this model.
Grygum: No, no, a lot of these would have scorn for local history. It's not their specialty.
GM: Actually, that's a good point. That seems like something that… okay, so…
GM: I think it would be more amusing if you have the, so you know a guy.
GM: Oh my god.
GM: You know a guy.
Grygum: We've definitely talked to a lot of people while we've been here, so we've probably picked up on those who know the key.
GM: So you do… you do manage to acquire one of the scholars who happens to be familiar with the area, so…
GM: He's very excited about the opportunity to, come with you.
GM: And ask whether he can just take a moment to go get some… a few things in the knobs and nabs.
Grygum: Yeah, does he have the dust of Mechanus?
GM: No, unfortunately, the dust of Mechanus… Mechanus is a particular plane, so… Regardless of.
Grygum: Oh, we might be in trouble if we can't get some.
Grygum: Unless it's just some sort of dry lubricant, it kind of implies that it is. It says to sprinkle it on dormant gears.
GM: So…
Thorin: Is the Dust of Mechanus Coke?
GM: Nope.
Grygum: That would be an expensive lubricant.
Thorin: I'm just saying.
Daz: Huh.
GM: So, here goes.
GM: So, who goes,
GM: Well, Mechanus happens to be a plane.
GM: is one of the planes of… one of the planes in the cosmic Wheel.
GM: And… the dust of Mechanus, is… is, could be anything. It could be…
GM: dust from that plane, it could be dust from… it could be, you know, killing one of those creatures. Whenever they die, they turn into dust, because they're not from this… they're not from the primaterial plane.
Thorin: Have we killed one of those? Can we get one of those?
GM: Let's see…
Thorin: He has Glabbagool, if he has any, like, squirreled away somewhere.
GM: Zalthir says, no, I do not.
Grygum: I, I ask whether it's any relation to the Dust of Suleiman.
GM: No, no, it's not, hold on. But they do point out that they're… I just need to check something, give me one second.
Grygum: I mean, the description really makes it sound like it's a form of preventative maintenance for these gears.
Grygum: Yes.
GM: That, that, that, that, so that's the… that's another option. You can try to see if you actually do need it.
Zalthir: I mean, can someone plane shift us and we just go kill some stuff and come back?
GM: Well, I mean, it turns out… so the house of… it turns out there is a House of Mechanus. It's a large rectangular blue… with a blue straight roof and appended clock tower. It sits between the Immortal Chambers and Founders Court. It is a library dedicated to construction, engineering, and technology.
GM: Apparently, there are 13 Modrons that are currently working there.
GM: Under the direction of Spanner, the librarian.
Zalthir: Sorry, 13 whats?
GM: Modrons, those are creatures from that plane.
Zalthir: Oh!
Grygum: Oh, my God.
Thorin: I don't want to kill any of them if they're just librarians, I don't.
Grygum: Why do we have to kill him?
Thorin: Do they, like, sneeze? Does it, like, sneeze dust or something? I mean, like, you know…
Grygum: I think we can just ask them for their advice, or, you know, if they've got a bag of dust that we can borrow.
GM: Alright.
GM: Yes, and I do not need to kill them. That is one of many solutions to the problem.
Grygum: Probably they're academics.
Thorin: You know, we don't kill librarians.
GM: No.
Thorin: They're our friends.
GM: Okay.
Zalthir: Have we killed a librarian before?
Thorin: But they attacked us first.
Zalthir: I'm sure.
Thorin: was justified.
Daz: Baz remembers that in the book that Milo wrote, that they actually had the, what was it? The…
Daz: A gift from the librarian, letter, or something?
GM: Yes, yes.
Daz: I mean… He muses that something like that would be useful now.
GM: Gross.
GM: Okay.
GM: Right.
GM: Okay, so, you arrive at the, at his… at their… where they're located, and, Modrons… let me just make sure if I don't accidentally give… tell you the wrong description.
GM: Let me just… I'll just show… there should be a way for me to do this,
GM: I spelled correctly, no, of course I didn't, because that would have been too easy.
GM: Modron.
GM: I did spell it correctly.
GM: I do that change.
GM: Anyway, a Modron, so it's like a box with two hands and little eyes.
GM: Let me see…
Zalthir: It sounds cute. Is it cute?
Grygum: Sounds like a little robot.
Thorin: Nemo?
GM: Let's see what…
Thorin: You know who BMO is?
GM: No… who's he?
Thorin: From, oh god, it's from a cartoon.
Zalthir: Oh, heh.
GM: Right.
Thorin: From Adventure Time.
Zalthir: Adventure Time, Ants.
GM: No, I do not want this.
GM: No, go away, stop, stop, stop.
Thorin: I'm sure they're, like, BMO.
Thorin: Here, I'll put that in the, Discord, too.
Thorin: All I'm doing is sending images your way. There we go. That's BMO.
Daz: Alright.
GM: Okay, so if you want to know what they are…
GM: I just put a link in the Zoom chat.
GM: Which points to them.
Thorin: Oh, what's not so bad.
Daz: Yeah, okay, third…
GM: And in the role chat 20 chat. Oh, wow.
Thorin: Mo.
Grygum: They look hilarious.
GM: No.
Zalthir: Not as cute as I was hoping, but okay.
Grygum: I don't know, I like the one that looks like two stack boxes.
Zalthir: Kinda creepy face.
Grygum: Mmm, yeah.
GM: Alright.
GM: So, yes, so it's kind of like a box with hands.
GM: They are, so, Spanner.
GM: is sitting… is sitting there looking at you. The… the thing about Mechanus is that it's all very mechanical, so everybody's moving in tight circles.
GM: everything that's carefully organized, it's sort of like an OCD person's wet dream.
Grygum: He looks…
GM: The gnome looks at you and asks you, what are you looking for? What is it that you're hoping to get?
Grygum: Well, we believe we have a situation where we need to lubricate some machinery, and the suggested lubricant was dust of Mechanus, and we thought you might have a line on some.
GM: Well, are you…
GM: He pauses and says, well, it is a well-known fact that the dust from the plane of Mechanus is, in fact, the most perfect of all lubricants.
Grygum: Well, how… how may we obtain some?
Grygum: We appreciate its positive qualities.
GM: He goes, that's an excellent question. So, there are two known ways to secure a secure such a thing.
Grygum: One of them asking politely.
GM: There's a stunned moment of silence.
Thorin: It's not polite when you interrupt.
Grygum: Oh, I'm sorry, please, please, please continue. I apologize.
GM: I mean, sorry, like, you've come to his place of work, and you're not going to give him an opportunity to meander for at least 10 minutes?
Grygum: Well,
Grygum: I actually don't know how urgent it is, but there might be a villain prepared to do villainous things if we're not in a hurry.
GM: Alright, so roll your… okay, so there's… it basically boils down to, one of the two approaches.
GM: The first is, you can,
GM: So, he goes, he goes, the only way for… the only way to obtain dust from the plane of Mechanus would be to kill one of my Modrons, which is absolutely, unacceptable.
GM: A second attempt, a second approach, might be to use some special tools my ModeRons have in fact created.
Thorin: That sounds like a better.
Grygum: Let's try it, although, it… is it ever awkward that you're full of extremely, like, valuable things?
GM: Up until today, it has never been an issue.
Grygum: Oh, okay. That's good. We won't make it an issue.
GM: Yes, he goes. Now, the problem is that these are very unique and special items.
Grygum: the tools?
GM: Yes, the tools.
GM: And so I will need something for collateral.
Grygum: -Oh.
Thorin: We don't need to keep the tools, we just need the dust.
GM: Oh, you… he pauses and says, but what guarantee will I have with the tooth? There's, like, this pause, sort of like, you know, he's very confused. Roll your persuasion, because that was a very good,
GM: Idea.
Grygum: Thorin, why don't you…
Thorin: My persuasion is negative 1, so you guys tell me.
Grygum: Oh, well… I'll do my, 14.
Thorin: I'll do mine. What do we got here?
Thorin: I need to reload.
GM: He, he accepts the,
GM: He accepts the offer.
GM: but insists that, Zalthir and…
GM: Glabbagool. I have to, he wants to study Zalthir and Glabbagool's construction, for its perfect symmetry, mechanical symmetry.
GM: And says that he's willing to give it as long as Zalthir and Glabbagool are willing to sit through a brief interview.
GM: I know.
Zalthir: We are… I consult with Zalthir. We're game as long as you give us constructive feedbacks. I've said we may better…
Zalthir: symbiotically serve our Zen cause.
GM: Always, always be selling.
GM: I'll keep that in mind.
GM: But I'll have to wait until after you go through this, because the question and answer period will be quite complicated. But yes, he… there is… he sort of turns around and speaks in this mechanistic language that you can't really possibly understand, and can't even figure out how a gnome is actually able to make those sounds.
GM: At which point in time, all the Modrons sort of engage in sort of a hypothet… you assume are talking to each other as they kind of move their arms and bodies around in sort of a mechanized dance. It's all very, very, very creepy.
GM: With that piece of information, with that, you guys can head down the stairs to the…
GM: So you can now head down the stairs. Alright, so what step are you gonna…
Grygum: Did we… did we make the dust already?
GM: No, you have the tool, which is an alternative.
Thorin: So I feel like there's a trick question, because it's like, he's 97 years old, and you're like, what, Steph? And we said 97, you keep asking us. Is there something else we should know?
GM: No, I'm… I'm the GM, that's my job, to ask you where you were precisely standing.
GM: Before, before.
Thorin: I'm… I'm suspicious.
Grygum: I, I go down 97 steps, and
Thorin: I keep my distance. Alright, so…
Grygum: And I… I res…
GM: Hold on.
Grygum: prophecy.
GM: Oh, is it, Zalthir?
GM: Are you standing next to him, or, like, where are you standing relative to.
Zalthir: I'll be on 97.
GM: Alright. Are they… Daz?
Grygum: Big… are they big steps?
GM: No, I mean, like, you can be a 96 or a 95, but not a 97. I mean, you two of you can be on it, like, all four of you, if you squeeze in and, like, are nice and cuddly with each other.
Grygum: Yeah, I guess the question is above or below, huh?
Zalthir: I mean, I can also fly, like…
Grygum: Oh, hover, very nice.
GM: You can hover, right?
Zalthir: Right.
GM: Right, and you have a potion of flying.
Zalthir: Huh?
GM: Daz, what are you gonna do?
Daz: I mean, good on.
GM: Now, where are you gonna sit? Are you gonna stand on the stair, or…
GM: above, below.
Daz: Where's my health right now?
Daz: I'm good. I'm, like, I can go anywhere. I'll… I'll… being… having clear view and letting ranged weapons hit would be good, so I'll stay a little high.
GM: Seat 96, 95, 93, 92, 90…
Grygum: You're gonna, like, stay low?
GM: I'm just asking, man.
Daz: I don't know, like…
Zalthir: While Daz is pondering, because in all this…
Daz: I think anytime you ask questions like this, it's followed by a rule for.
Grygum: Yeah.
Thorin: It's like, it's gonna be like, okay, your positions are locked in, roll for initiative.
Daz: It's hard to tell.
Grygum: Sometimes the damn is true.
Daz: I'll take up the rear in case somebody attacks us from behind. My stuff is pretty good, and if I'm at the top of the stairs, I'll be able to see with my ranged
Daz: attacks for…
Thorin: And I think if something's gonna happen, I might as well be at the front, because I can… frickin'…
Thorin: Tank it, but still.
GM: Alright.
Zalthir: Did we have a short rest in there somewhere?
GM: You have…
Daz: Not, as far as I know.
GM: No.
Zalthir: No… no short rest.
GM: Yes.
Zalthir: So, before we do this, can someone give me a quick heal?
Grygum: Sure, yeah. How much, could you use?
Zalthir: I'm short 27.
Grygum: Oh, yeah, let me find a good one then.
GM: Alright.
Daz: roll first, so… I'm waiting for it, it's coming.
GM: Alright, actually, no. Alright.
Grygum: Yeah, you got 44 of them back, so that's.
Zalthir: Thank you.
Grygum: It's overkill, but it'll do…
GM: All but Daz.
GM: Who's standing up sufficiently high.
Daz: Oh, shit.
GM: Begin to fall down a vast, circular well.
GM: Plummeting.
Zalthir: Can I grab the other two and open my wings?
Daz: Hold on…
Grygum: I'm looking for an appropriate spell, but I'm not finding one, so I, I wave goodbye as he plummets.
Grygum: We'll see you at the bottom.
Daz: Do I have any way to stop it from happening?
GM: While you guys are trying to figure out what spell to cast, while… while Grygum is holding… while Zalthir is using his strength to hold you guys, the two… two of you, float.
Daz: Can you describe the details? So, like, did the stairs turn into a slide, and then they started to move?
GM: Yes.
Daz: Or, like, is there debris?
Grygum: No, we're doing the Scooby-Doo thing again.
Daz: What's in the well? Like, what's around?
GM: A 10-foot-long section of the stairs suddenly gives way.
Daz: The way, like, starts to fall?
GM: Yes, falls, yes.
Daz: Okay.
Grygum: Am I okay on step 97?
GM: No, that's literally… no, what happened?
Grygum: Oh.
GM: That's… anybody standing between 101 and 90… no, 102 and 93.
Grygum: Huh.
GM: is caught in the hinge, so… Yes, so…
Daz: So… and… I can just use a regular action, like, I can respond to this right away, right?
GM: Yes, yes.
Daz: Okay, well then, I would like to cast, Telekinesis.
Daz: And hold the stairs so that it does not fall.
Daz: Or at least prevent it from falling anymore, and then.
GM: Alright.
Daz: Let me back up.
GM: Make… make some dexterity saving throws, just to see if you guys manage, like, whether he caught it in time.
Daz: one.
Thorin: What makes the difference?
Daz: So maybe no.
Grygum: 16.
GM: 16? Oh.
Daz: Oh, there are dexterity saving throws, okay.
Thorin: I, I think I… okay.
Thorin: Give me a second here. So…
Daz: 16, 27…
Thorin: Wait, did it do it?
Thorin: Damn it, what is it?
Thorin: It's not, like…
GM: Oh, Grygum had… Grygum made it.
Thorin: U20 minus 1, okay, so… I got a 3, what? I got a 2, but I can…
GM: Suffice it to say that.
Thorin: advantage. Okay, so…
GM: Right, since the… since… okay, roll, roll your luck point.
Thorin: Oh, that time I got a 5, that's so much better.
GM: Alright, well… as a result of that, but I'm presuming Daz will… sorry.
GM: So he starts to fall down the thing. The rest of you have managed to hold onto the stairs, and I'm going to assume can scramble your way to safety. What do you want to do about Thorin who's falling?
Thorin: Well, I'm gonna try one more time.
Zalthir: I mean, can I just grab one?
Thorin: You can re-roll it with a plus 9 bonus, and then you must use the new roll, so this would be a…
Thorin: Roll D20 plus 8.
GM: Alright.
Grygum: Good luck!
Thorin: Or, no, okay, so, wait, plus 9… yeah, plus, plus 8, okay.
Zalthir: Okay.
GM: Oh, okay.
Thorin: time.
GM: Big time, though.
Thorin: Gross.
GM: Big time flexible.
Thorin: Okay.
GM: Okay, so Mark Johnson sent me, I just want to leave this for Zalthir, because I'm sure he will enjoy it. Yeah, you told me about Greece retroactively revoking your degree, unless you mean there was a third.
GM: So, given… there was.
Daz: There was another.
GM: There was another. Thank you.
Daz: You're gonna keep the style of speech going.
GM: Yeah, there was another, thank you, thank you.
Daz: Or there is another, I guess. It doesn't matter. There was, there is.
GM: Doesn't matter. Now, I just… he's very… he, like, for those of you who don't know, whenever Mark wanted to give a speech about something he didn't want to do, he would point out that he…
GM: Quit high school without a degree because he was fed up with people telling him what to do.
Zalthir: Yes.
GM: And so we wanted to keep that in mind as we were telling him to do things that he wanted to.
Zalthir: Yeah, that's Mark.
GM: Yeah, that was, like, a whole thing for him. So when I found out that my high school diploma was revoked by the Greek government.
GM: I kid you not.
Grygum: What?
GM: So it turns out that…
GM: I went to a school that had 13 years of high school, because British schools do O-levels and A levels.
Grygum: Yeah.
GM: They did, they no longer do them. And so A-levels are essentially grades 12 and 13.
GM: And so my high school…
Grygum: immortalized in Harry Potter.
GM: Yes. And so, grade 12, However, they gave us a diploma at the end of grade 12,
GM: So that you could go to a U.S. college at grade 12 if you didn't want to spend the extra year to do the A-levels.
GM: And the Greek government had… the Greek government noticed that they had never actually sanctioned those degrees.
GM: And nobody had cared, but apparently in 2001, somebody cared.
GM: And, as a result of that caring,
GM: they decided that it wasn't… it didn't count as a full high school degree, but it counted as if you had graduated from grade 11 from high school. And that's really important in Greece, because there's a whole bunch of things that hinge on whether you have that degree or not.
GM: not, you know, like, in Greece, there's a lot more regulations and rules, etc, for everything. So yeah, so I told Mark that I… I, too, am a high school dropout.
Zalthir: Huh.
Thorin: You didn't do the 13th year, did you then go to a U.S. college?
GM: I did do the 13th year, but I don't have a high school degree, so I blessed myself.
Zalthir: Wait, wait…
Thorin: But what… do you get a degree after the 13th year? Wouldn't that be a high school degree?
Thorin: E-levels degree.
GM: That's an alibles thing.
Thorin: Okay, so it's just nomenclature here.
GM: Yes, yes, but, I mean, with Mark, this was such a point of bragging that it… you have to understand, I… I endured… I endured years of this.
Grygum: I, I…
Zalthir: It amuses me he never brought it up in front of me, because, you know… Yeah, but you were never.
GM: or try to give them direction, whereas I… where I was.
Zalthir: Yeah.
Grygum: I guess as someone who completed a PhD, it's hard to… it's hard to claim that I won't put up with any degree of bullshit.
Daz: Exactly. That PhD, isn't that, like… doesn't it actually stand for, I will put up with all kinds of bullshit? It does!
Grygum: Yeah, yeah, it's Latin, but that's what it means.
GM: Yeah, Zalthir, what happened to the gym?
Zalthir: It's over there! Now it's its own huge room.
GM: Did you buy a new house?
Zalthir: Yes.
GM: Oh, congratulations.
Zalthir: Wow, thanks.
GM: Where?
Zalthir: SF, Pack Hearts.
GM: Gotcha.
GM: Alright, folks.
Zalthir: All right.
GM: And with that, We won't… we will end.
Zalthir: Alright, have a good night.
Thorin: See y'all later.
Grygum: Good night, see you.